(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
みんなと見届ける！4周年カウントダウン
Watch with everyone! 4th Anniversary Countdown
こんみこー！
Konmiko!
みんなー！
Everyone!
さくらみこの4周年カウントダウンライブへ
Welcome to Sakura Miko's 4th Anniversary
ようこそにぇー！
Countdown Live, nyee!
今日はね、
Today,
ゲストもたくさん
many guests
来てくれるから...
will be coming...
みんなと見届ける！
4周年カウントダウン
Watching with everyone!
4th Anniversary Countdown
0！
0!
Baby Dance Live
Sakura Miko 4th Anniversary
始まりの瞬間さ
It's the moment of the beginning
追い風は砂ばかり
The tailwind is just full of sand
上げた 立ち止まってられない
I raised my head, I can't stay still
うまくやり過ごしても
Even if I manage to get by smoothly
本当に欲しいもの
The thing I truly want
抱きしめなきゃ いつも満たされない
If I don't embrace it, I'll never be satisfied
探しに行こう
Let's go look for it
果てしない青空へ
To the endless blue sky
刻む足跡 鮮やかに
Carving footprints vividly
君と描き出そう
Let's draw it out with you
走り出せ
Start running
誰も知らない未来
A future that no one knows
飛び込んだ あの時に
To the time when I dived in
輝いた
It shone
君の瞳に映った
Reflected in your eyes
素晴らしい
A wonderful
明日がほら
Look, tomorrow
僕らを待っているから
Is waiting for us
どんなに誤魔化しても
No matter how much I hide it
これこそが現実
This is the reality
さだめも もう目反らせない
Even fate, I can't look away anymore
誰かの幸せとか
Someone's happiness or something
横取りしたくなっちゃうけど
I end up wanting to snatch it away
それでも満たされない
But even then, I'm not satisfied
さわやかな悩みは
Refreshing worries
胸焦がす真実は
The heart-scorching truth
見つめる瞳に
In the eyes that gaze
響き合え　ときめきと
Resonate with the excitement
始めよう！
Let's begin!
朝焼けが
The sunrise
いつか夢見た　未来
Is the future I once dreamed of
照らしてくれてるから
Because it's shining for me
手を繋ぎ
Holding hands
今すぐに　飛びだそう
Let's fly out right now
素晴らしい　明日は　ほら
Look, a wonderful tomorrow
僕らのためにあるから
Exists for our sake
迷っても　失っても
Even if I get lost, even if I lose things
明日なの？　向き合って
Is it tomorrow? Facing it
終わらない　物語は　今日もまた　色を変えて
The unending story changes color again today
瞬くよ　さぁ瞳開けて
It sparkles, now open your eyes
走り出せ　誰も知らない未来
Run towards the future no one knows
飛び越そう　その時に
Let's leap over when the time comes
輝いた　君の瞳　導いた
Your sparkling eyes guided me
素晴らしい　明日はもう
A wonderful tomorrow is already
僕らを待っているから
Waiting for us
1, 2, 参拝！みこみこみこー！
1, 2, worship! Miko miko miko!
みこちの4周年ライブに来てくれてありがとう！最後まで盛り上がっていくぞー！
Thank you for coming to Mikochi's 4th anniversary live! Let's keep the energy up until the end!
ついに来たよお待たせ
I'm finally here, thanks for waiting
待ちに待った　うへへへ
The long-awaited... uhehehe
電脳世界からやってきた
I came from the cyber world
巫女兼バーチャル巫女アイドル
Shrine maiden and virtual miko idol
私はそうエリート
That's right, I'm elite
なんてったってエリート
No matter what, I'm elite
エリートみこ、エリートアイドル
Elite Miko, elite idol
サマになってきちゃってんじゃん
Doesn't it look like I've got it down?
意地悪も泣き虫も　神様も崇めたら
Meanies, crybabies, and even God... if you worship them
みこパワー全開　幸せわけてあげてもいいんだよ
Miko power at full throttle, I don't mind sharing some happiness
みこちゃんはエリートで！
Miko-chan is elite!
みこみこみこでハレノチハレ
Miko miko miko, sunny then sunny
さくらさくら咲きさくら
Cherry blossoms, cherry blossoms, blooming blossoms
みこみこみこで無病息災
Miko miko miko, good health and longevity
明日から本気出す
I'll get serious starting tomorrow
みこみこみこでハレノチハレ
Miko miko miko, sunny then sunny
今夜はほねぬきに（しちゃうぞ）
Tonight I'll leave you spellbound
幸せも最高潮　みこみこみこでみんな笑顔になれ
Happiness is at its peak, everyone smile with miko miko miko
1, 2, 参拝！みこみこみこー！
1, 2, worship! Miko miko miko!
ちょっとだけ休憩タイム
Just a little break time
マイペースだけど許してね
It's my own pace, but please forgive me
実はこれも修行のうちです
Actually, this is also part of my training
そんなわけはなくなくなくない
There's no way that's... not not not true
わたしはそうエリート（エリート！）
I am elite (Elite!)
嘘じゃないよエリート（ドヤ！）
It's not a lie, I'm elite (Smug!)
エリートみこ、エリートアイドル？
Elite Miko, elite idol?
魂こめて頑張っていきましょー！
Let's do our best with all our soul!
さくらもよう曇り空　雨の日も問題ない
Cherry blossom patterns, cloudy sky, even rainy days are no problem
みこパワー全開で　あっぱれパレード笑顔さあ行こうよ
With Miko power at full throttle, let's go with smiles on a splendid parade
チャンネル登録してくりぇ〜！
Please subscribe to the channel~!
みこみこみこでハレノチハレ
Miko miko miko, sunny then sunny
さくらさくら咲きさくら
Cherry blossoms, cherry blossoms, blooming blossoms
みこみこみこで無病息災
Miko miko miko, good health and longevity
ピーマンは残さず食べようね
Eat all your bell peppers, okay?
みこみこみこでハレノチハレ
Miko miko miko, sunny then sunny
神様もほねぬきに（しちゃった）
I've even spellbound God
元気も最高潮　みこみこみこでみんな笑顔になれ
Vigor is at its peak, everyone smile with miko miko miko
1, 2, お間違えた！
1, 2, I made a mistake!
マイネームイズエリート☆
My Name is Elite☆
にゃっはろー！みんな楽しんでるー？
Nyaho-lo! Is everyone enjoying themselves?
ここからはスーパーみこみこタイム！
From here on, it's Super Miko-Miko Time!
絶対に遅れずについてこいよ！
Make sure you don't fall behind and keep up!
みんなで、いっせーのーで！
Everyone, on the count of three!
はい！
One!
みーこ！みーこ！
Miko! Miko!
みこはエリート！
Miko is an elite!
E-L-I-T-E
エリート！エリート！イェイ！
Elite! Elite! Yay!
よし、もう一回張り切っていくぞ！
Alright, let's keep the energy up one more time!
みみみみこみこみーで　うっうーにゃにゃ
Mi-mi-mi-mi Miko-Miko-Mi, uh-uh nya-nya
さくらさくら咲けさくらみこ
Sakura, Sakura, bloom Sakura Miko
みこみこみーで　にゃっはろにゃっはろー
Miko-Miko-Mi, nyahallo-nyahallo
今日も元気に　チャームポイントは巫女ですから！
Enthusiastic today too! My charm point is being a shrine maiden!
みみみみこみこみーで　うっうーにゃにゃ
Mi-mi-mi-mi Miko-Miko-Mi, uh-uh nya-nya
全時はにゃにゃにゃにゃにゃーにゃにゃ
All the time nya-nya-nya-nya-nya-nya-nya
幸せの天才　みこみこみーで
A genius of happiness, Miko-Miko-Mi
笑顔になれ　ダンスタイム！
Let's see those smiles, it's dance time!
みこみこみー　イェイ！
Miko-Miko-Mi, Yay!
最後にもう一回！　みこみこみー　イェイ！
One last time! Miko-Miko-Mi, Yay!
はい！ということで始まりました！
Yes! And so, it's begun!
さくらみこ４周年ライブ
Sakura Miko 4th Anniversary Live
Baby Dance Live!
いやー、ちょっと初手でトラブルがあって開始遅れちゃいましたけど
Wow, there was a bit of trouble at the start, so the beginning was delayed.
ま、これもさくらみこなのかな、しょうがないのかな
Well, I guess that's just Sakura Miko's way, it can't be helped.
ポンの呪いなのかな、という感じですが
Maybe it's the curse of 'pon' (clumsiness)...
みなさん楽しんでますかー？
Is everyone having fun?
みこぴー見てるー？
Mikopi, are you watching?
見て見て、こちらですね、じゃん！
Look, look, it's this, ta-da!
今回のライブのロゴをね、このTシャツにプリントしてもらったんだよ！
I had the logo for this live printed on this T-shirt!
めっちゃ可愛くない？ライブっぽくない？イェーイ！
Isn't it super cute? Doesn't it feel like a live concert? Yay!
可愛い！
Cute!
今回のライブのハッシュタグは、こちら！こちら！
The hashtag for this live is... here! Here!
＃さくらみこ４周年
#SakuraMiko4thAnniversary
こちらね、たくさん呟いてトレンド入りさせてください！
Please tweet using this a lot and get it trending!
ありがとね、みんな！
Thanks, everyone!
まだまだまだまだ続きますから
There's still much more to come.
みんな盛り上がって、いこー！！
So everyone, keep the excitement going! Let's go!!
CLEAR
風に乗って　鳥に乗って　私より自由かな
Riding the wind, riding a bird, are they freer than me?
翼がないなら走ってく　行きたいところまで
If I don't have wings, I'll run to wherever I want to go.
できるよね
I can do it, right?
Going going going going...
想像とは　いつも違って
Reality is always different from what I imagined
何もかも完璧とはいかないけど
Nothing ever goes perfectly, but
心の底に　泉があるの
At the bottom of my heart, there's a spring
どんなに落ち込んでもまた透明なもので満たされていく
No matter how depressed I feel, it's filled again with clarity
これって　これって　なんて気持ちなの
This feeling... what should I call it?
熱くて痛くてくすぐったくて涙が出そう
It's hot, it's painful, it's ticklish, and it's making me cry
風に乗って　鳥に乗って　私より自由かな
Riding the wind, riding a bird, are they freer than me?
翼がないなら走ってく　行きたいところまで
If I don't have wings, I'll run to wherever I want to go.
できるよね
I can do it, right?
Going going going going...
他の子にあって　私にないもの
Things other girls have that I don't
分かってはいるけど　つい比べちゃうよ
I know them, but I still end up comparing myself
答え合わせなんてしたくない
I don't want to check if my answers are right
みんなと同じじゃなくても私にできること見つけたいな
Even if I'm not like everyone else, I want to find what I can do
夢って　愛って　本当はよく知らない
Dreams and love... I don't really know them well yet
どんな色どんな形どこからやってくるの
What color are they? What shape? Where do they come from?
願って　それだけじゃ叶わない
Just wishing won't make it come true
自信がなくても始めるんだ　いつかじゃなく今
Even without confidence, I'll start, not someday but now
できるよね？
I can do it, right?
Going Going Going Going Go!!
泉がここにあるのも
The reason there's a spring here,
私を司る皆の名前が
And the names of everyone who defines me...
ああ　何があっても　枯れたりしない
Ah, no matter what happens, they'll never wither
諦めたつもりでもまた透明なもので満たされてゆく
Even when I feel like giving up, I'm filled with something pure again
これって　これって　なんて気持ちなの？
This feeling... just what is it?
熱くて痛くてくすぐったくて涙が出そう
It's so hot, painful, and ticklish, I'm almost in tears
風で　鳥で　私より自由かな？
Like the wind or the birds, are they freer than me?
翼がないなら走ってくわ行きたいところまで
If I have no wings, I'll run to wherever I want to go
できるよね？
I can do it, right?
Going Going Going Going Go!!
竹取オーバーナイトセンセーション
Taketori Overnight Sensation
とにかくにも今恋に落ちたわけであります
Anyway, it seems I've fallen in love now
前前前世あーらら歌え踊れや心はやる
Lifetimes ago, ah-la-la, sing and dance, my heart is racing
やれやれ天女の瞳をいたずらに
Good grief, teasing the eyes of a celestial maiden
そんな私目が帝と相容れるその理由はひ・み・つ・で・す・の
The reason I get along with the emperor is a S-E-C-R-E-T
何年待てわさだめの子
How many years must I wait, child of fate?
月のまにまにお手を拝借
At the mercy of the moon, let me borrow your hands
そのまま運命一五センチパッパッパッ眠れない
Just like that, destiny is 15cm away, pa-pa-pa, I can't sleep
そのまま将来の光景先手打って問答無用
Just like that, striking first at the future, no questions asked
月に背を向けたなら夜明けまで
If you turn your back to the moon, until dawn
わがまま姫君愛のしるしヘイ！
Selfish princess, a sign of love, hey!
とにかくにも今恋に落ちたわけであります
Anyway, it seems I've fallen in love now
独酌点睛さあ特権ディナー大盤振る舞い酔う現象
Drinking alone to finish it off, a grand feast, a dizzying sight
そのうち薄れた富士の煙
Before long, the smoke from Mt. Fuji faded
ゆるり私目が君のその瞳思いのままで何処までもゆこう
Slowly, as I please, let's go anywhere with those eyes of yours
そうして時間も惜しむ
And so, begrudging even the time
お嫁にひとついい駆け引きです
It's a good bargain for a bride
そのまま天国感情先手打ってパッパッパッ眠れない
Just like that, heavenly emotions, pa-pa-pa, I can't sleep
そのまま退屈な自由より空へダイブ
Just like that, dive into the sky rather than boring freedom
月に背を向けたなら夜明けまで
If you turn your back to the moon, until dawn
わがままな私許してねねね
Please forgive my selfishness, ne-ne-ne
あっちは恋して
Over there, falling in love
こっちは欲しくて
Over here, wanting it
あっちは恋して
Over there, falling in love
こっちはトントン？
Over here, a rhythmic beat?
あっちも欲しくて
Wanting it over there too
こっちも欲しいな
I want it over here too
あっちも欲しくて
Wanting it over there too
ほらあっちは恋して
Look, falling in love over there
Follow me follow me honey
知ってる 自由を探すことなんて今更
I know, it's a bit late to be looking for freedom
馬鹿げてる 隣の籠に飛び移った 鳥みたいじゃない？
It's foolish, isn't it? Just like a bird that flew into the neighboring cage.
知ってる どうやってもどこにでもあるような
I know, no matter what, it's just something you can find anywhere
二律背反 つまり全身全霊 今は嘘なんかじゃない
Antinomy, in other words, heart and soul, right now it's not a lie
なんかから
From something...
運命死後選択パパパ 眠れない
Fate, post-mortem choice, pa pa pa, I can't sleep
このままホライゾン境界線切っても問答無用
Continuing like this, even if I cut the Horizon boundary, there's no use arguing
宇宙に向き合ったのよ だけど
I faced the universe, but...
イフにドート アハニハニホヘト
If and doubt, aha ni ha ni ho he to
わがまま姫君 暁のしるし ヘイ！
The selfish princess, the mark of dawn, Hey!
今日から君の好きなとこ
From today, the things I like about you
一日一個伝えよう
I'll tell you one per day
365回
365 times
時々貸しちゃって バッキュン！
Lend them to me sometimes, Bang!
小悪魔だってかまわない！
I don't care if I'm a little devil!
こっちおいでよもう
Come over here already
もしもしてまだ片思い
Perhaps it's still a one-sided love
たまに甘えてくるくせに
Even though you act spoiled sometimes
もしもして転がされてる？
Perhaps I'm being played?
一目惚れして毎日通ってた
I fell in love at first sight and visited every day
君と目が合うたびに
Every time our eyes meet
恋が爆発
Love explodes
今日から君の好きなとこ
From today, the things I like about you
一日一個伝えよう
I'll tell you one per day
365回
365 times
時々貸しちゃって バッキュン！
Lend them to me sometimes, Bang!
他の子見たり（のんのん）
Looking at other girls (no no)
携帯ばっか見たり（のんのん）
Only looking at your phone (no no)
君だけに見せるよ
I'll only show you
偉いのがご褒美 ギュッ！
Being good is the reward, Squeeze!
たまにはお出かけどう？
How about going out once in a while?
いつも部屋デートばかりじゃん
It's always just dates in our room
もちろんそれでもいいけど
Of course that's fine too, but...
僕だってオシャレしたいし
I want to dress up too
昼や夜もあっちこっち追い回して
Chasing you around here and there day and night
僕がいないと君
When I'm not around, you...
何もできないくせに
Even though you can't do anything
毎日君の機嫌取って
Trying to please you every day
一日一回ハグして
Hugging you once a day
何百回何千回
Hundreds of times, thousands of times
愛を伝えちゃって バッキュン！
Expressing my love, Bang!
一人で道歩いたり（のんのん）
Walking the streets alone (no no)
ゲームばっかしたり（のんのん）
Only playing games (no no)
君だけに見せるよ
I'll only show you
偉いのがご褒美 ギュッ！
Being good is the reward, Squeeze!
帰り遅くなっちゃう時だって
Even when I'm late coming home
急いで帰るからね
I'll hurry back, okay?
寄り道せずに会いましゅ
I'll see you without making any stops
ただいま！
I'm home!
おかえりもなし
No 'welcome home'
よしよしもなし
No head pats either
それでもいいよ
But that's okay
だから一緒に見てね
So let's watch together, okay?
ねえねえどこ隠れてるの？
Hey, hey, where are you hiding?
もしもして出ていっちゃった？
Perhaps you've left?
急に噛みついてきた
Suddenly you bit me
君は小悪魔だね
You're a little devil, aren't you?
今日から君の好きなとこ
From today, the things I like about you
一日一個伝えよう
I'll tell you one per day
365回
365 times
時々貸しちゃって バッキュン！
Lend them to me sometimes, Bang!
他の子見たり（のんのん）
Looking at other girls (no no)
携帯ばっか見たり（のんのん）
Only looking at your phone (no no)
君だけに見せるよ
I'll only show you
偉いのがご褒美 ギュッ！
Being good is the reward, Squeeze!
咲かせや咲かせ Supercell
Sakaseya Sakase by Supercell
今となれば名残惜しき
Now that it's come to this, I'm feeling reluctant to part
刻は歩くよ 宵の灯
Time walks on, the evening light
限りあるものが歌う
Things with an end are singing
眠り 冬を越えて
Sleeping through the winter
待ち遠しあうね 桜花見月
Waiting for each other, the month of cherry blossom viewing
薫れば情に 綴る文字が舞う
When the scent lingers, the characters I write dance in my heart
諸行無常 かよい路かな
All things are impermanent, perhaps a passing path
今は漂う 此処に
Now drifting here
誰もが夢を描く
Everyone draws a dream
さあさあもっと 踊れや踊れ
Come on, come on, dance more, dance
満まで鳴る子ならせ
Ring the naruko until it's full
花吹雪 咲かせや咲かせ
A blizzard of flowers, let them bloom, let them bloom
新しき春の息吹かれ
Breathed on by the new spring
雪解けて土香れば
When the snow melts and the soil smells sweet
名もなき芽 ゲラゲラと
Nameless sprouts laughing loudly
草は芽吹き 山笑う
The grass buds and the mountains laugh
眠り 冬を越えて
Sleeping through the winter
丁々発止 さあほいさ そこ退け
At it tooth and nail, come on, get out of the way
負けたらそれのめ 目回るまで
If you lose, drink it down until your head spins
諸行無常 楽しからぬこと
All things are impermanent, no more fun
今はただ 花向けて
Now just turn towards the flowers
皆が夢を描く
Everyone draws a dream
さあさあもっと 祝えや祝え
Come on, come on, celebrate more, celebrate
満まで祭り明かせ
Keep the festival going until the moon is full
皆が踊れ 咲かせや咲かせ
Everyone dance, let them bloom, let them bloom
新しき春の息吹かれ
Breathed on by the new spring
心もまた息吹く
The heart also breathes again
どんどこさわげ 山海から さあ役者
Make some noise, from mountains and seas, come on actors
踊る阿呆に 見る阿呆
Dancing fools and watching fools
感謝 感謝で 手をたたき 拍子にのれ
Gratitude, gratitude, clap your hands, get in the rhythm
どんどこさわげ 空大地まで 震わせろ
Make some noise, shake the sky and earth
どんどこさわげ 老いも若きも そいやさ
Make some noise, young and old alike, seiya-sa
さあさあもっと 踊れや踊れ
Come on, come on, dance more, dance
満まで鳴る子ならせ
Ring the naruko until it's full
花吹雪 咲かせや咲かせ
A blizzard of flowers, let them bloom, let them bloom
新しき春の息吹かれ
Breathed on by the new spring
さあさあもっと 祝えや祝え
Come on, come on, celebrate more, celebrate
満まで祭り明かせ
Keep the festival going until the moon is full
皆が踊れ 咲かせや咲かせ
Everyone dance, let them bloom, let them bloom
新しき春の息吹かれ
Breathed on by the new spring
心もまた息吹く
The heart also breathes again
咲かせや 咲かせ
Let them bloom, let them bloom
My Soul, Your Beats!
目覚めては繰り返す
Waking up, I repeat the cycle
眠い朝は
On sleepy mornings
襟のタイをきつく締め
I tighten the tie on my collar
教室のドアをくぐると
Passing through the classroom door
ほんの少し
Just a little bit
胸を張って歩き出せる
I can start walking with pride
そんな日常に吹き抜ける風
A wind blowing through such daily life
聞こえた気がした
I felt like I heard it
感じた気がしたんだ
I felt like I felt it
震え出す
Starting to tremble
今この胸で
Now in this chest
もう来る気がした
I felt like it was already coming
幾億の星が消えて
Billions of stars disappear
去っていくのを
Watching them leave
見送った
I saw them off
手を振った
I waved my hand
よかったね、と
Saying 'It was good'
道の途中
Along the path
おかしなものだと思う
I think it's a strange thing
私の中の時は止まってるのに
Even though time inside me has stopped
違う日々を生きてるように
As if living different days
誇りは雪のように降り積む
Pride piles up like snow
待ってる気がした
I felt like I was waiting
呼んでる気がしたんだ
I felt like I was being called
震え出す 今この時が
Trembling, this moment right now
見つけた気がした
I felt like I found it
失われた記憶が
The lost memories
呼び覚ました
Have awakened
物語
The story
永遠の
Eternal
その終わり
Its end
いつの間にか駆け出していた
Before I knew it, I had started running
あなたに手を引かれていた
You were leading me by the hand
昨日は遠く 明日はすぐ
Yesterday is far away, tomorrow is soon
そんな当たり前に
To such an obvious thing
心が躍った
My heart danced
聞こえた気がした
I felt like I heard it
感じた気がしたんだ
I felt like I felt it
震え出す この胸でもう
Trembling, already in this chest
来る気がした
I felt like it was coming
幾千の朝を越え
Crossing thousands of mornings
新しい陽が
A new sun
待ってる気がした
I felt like I was waiting
呼んでる気がしたんだ
I felt like I was being called
震えてるこの魂が
This trembling soul
見つけた気がした
Felt like it found it
幾億の夢のように
Like hundreds of millions of dreams
消え去る日を
The day it disappears
見送った
I watched it go
手を振った
I waved my hand
ありがとうと
Saying "thank you"
あの日と同じだ
It's the same as that day
違う色は指を刺されていた
Different colors were being pointed at
怖くて隠してた
I was scared and hiding it
同じ色になりかけていた
I was about to become the same color
明日から逃げるな
Don't run away from tomorrow
胸を張って輝け
Puff out your chest and shine
世界は広いよ
The world is wide
見てごらんよ
Go on and see
僕らを育てて
Nurture us
重い夢は貫け
Pierce through heavy dreams
ネガティブな自分置いていこうわ
Let's leave our negative selves behind
君の色が綺麗で勝った
Your color was beautiful and won
一つで世界彩っている
Coloring the world with just one
花火みたいで ほら
Like fireworks, see
照れないでいいんだよ
It's okay not to be shy
顔を上げて
Look up
特別な君でいて
Be the special you
やりたいことやらなきゃ損じゃん
It's a loss if you don't do what you want
人の夢取っちゃダメ
You can't take other people's dreams
君を楽しんで
Enjoy being yourself
見た目も違うのに
Even though we look different
同じレール歩かなきゃダメなの？
Do we have to walk on the same rail?
恥ずかしい夢だって
Even if it's an embarrassing dream
胸の隅に追いやっていた
I had pushed it to the corner of my heart
...いつか
...Someday,
君が忘れて
even if you forget,
忘れ去られなくなる
you won't be forgotten.
そんな嘘があるよ
There's such a lie.
ずっといるよ
I'll always be here.
今ワクワクになれる
Now we can be excited.
夢が街支配して
Dreams rule the city,
時間さえ忘れ笑っていていいの
you can even forget time and keep smiling.
君の色は名前なんてなくて見とれて世界輝かせている
Your color doesn't have a name, it captivates and makes the world shine.
星みたいでああ
Like a star, ah...
正解なんだよそのままの君で
You are correct just as you are.
特別な意味でいて
Please stay as someone special.
楽しいこと待ってたとちゃん迎えに行こう
Look, let's go meet the fun things that were waiting.
君の今君の本音だけ夢を歌え
Sing your dream with only your true feelings of now.
悲しみ増しても後悔はしないように
Even if sadness increases, so that you won't have regrets...
過ごせていますか胸に聞いて
Ask your heart, "Are you living well?"
呼吸をするために笑い合う日のために
To breathe, for the days we laugh together,
生きているんだよ真っ直ぐ泣いて
we are living, so cry your heart out.
届け！
Reach out!
君の色が綺麗でたった一つで世界彩っている
Your color is beautiful, it colors the world on its own.
花みたいでほら
Look, like a flower,
照れないでいいんだよ顔を上げて
you don't need to be shy, lift your head up.
特別な意味でいて
Please stay as someone special.
やりたいことやらなきゃ損じゃん正々堂々
If you don't do what you want, it's a waste, right? Fair and square.
人の夢それじゃダメ君を楽しめ
Someone else's dream won't do, enjoy yourself.
頑張ってる君に捧げる夢ファンファーレ
A Dream Fanfare dedicated to you who are doing your best.
光るなら
Hikaru Nara
雨上がりの虹も 凛と咲いた花も
Both the rainbow after the rain and the flower that bloomed so bravely,
色づき溢れ出す
they are beginning to overflow with color.
茜色の空 仰ぐ君に あの日 恋に落ちた
I fell in love with you that day as you looked up at the madder-red sky.
瞬間のドラマチック
A dramatic moment,
フィルムの中のひとコマ
a single frame within the film.
消えないよ心に刻むから
It won't fade away, for I'll carve it into my heart.
君だよ 君なんだよ 教えてくれた
It's you, you're the one who taught me.
暗闇も光るなら 星空になる
If even the darkness shines, it will become a starry sky.
悲しみを笑顔に もう隠さないで
Turn your sadness into a smile, don't hide it anymore.
煌めくどんな星も 君を照らすから
Because every sparkling star will shine upon you.
眠りも忘れて
Having forgotten even sleep,
迎えた朝日が やたらと突き刺さる
the morning sun that I met stabs at me so relentlessly.
低血圧な 曇った朝だって
Even on a low-blood-pressure, cloudy morning,
忘れる 君に会えば
I forget it all if I meet you.
静寂はロマンティック
Silence is romantic,
紅茶に溶けたシュガーのように
like sugar dissolved in black tea.
全身に巡るよ 君の声
Your voice courses through my entire body.
君だよ 君なんだよ 笑顔をくれた
It's you, you're the one who gave me a smile.
涙も光るなら 流星になる
If even the tears shine, they will become shooting stars.
傷付いたその手を もう離さないで
Don't ever let go of that wounded hand again.
願いを込めた空に 明日が来るから
For tomorrow will come to the sky filled with our wishes.
導いてくれた光は 君だよ
The light that guided me was you.
つられて僕も走り出した
Drawn along, I started running too.
知らぬ間にクロスし始めた
Before I knew it, we began to cross paths.
ほら今だ ここで光るなら
Look, now is the time to shine here
君だよ 君なんだよ 教えてくれた
It's you, it was you who told me
暗闇は終わるから
The darkness will end
君だよ 君なんだよ 教えてくれた
It's you, it was you who told me
暗闇も光るなら 星空になる
If even the darkness shines, it becomes a starry sky
悲しみを笑顔に もう隠さないで
Turn sadness into a smile, don't hide it anymore
煌めく どんな星も 君を照らすから
Because every twinkling star will shine on you
答えはいつでも 偶然？ 必然？
The answer is always... coincidence? Inevitable?
いつか選んだ道こそ 運命になる
The path we once chose will become destiny
握りしめた その希望も 不安も
That hope and anxiety you held tightly
きっと二人を動かす 光になるから
Will surely become the light that moves us both
はい！ということで！
All right! So!
なんと、しらけんメンバーにMCとして来てもらいました！
Somehow, I've had the Shiraken members come as MCs!
イェーイ！
Yay!
ドゥン！ドゥン！
Bam! Bam!
すごいなー
That's amazing.
えーちょっと、じゃあ、社長はこちらにいていただいて...
Um, well then, President, please stay over here...
しらけんなんでね
Because we're Shiraken.
おー！イェーイ！
Oh! Yay!
ぼりら！
Gorilla!
しらぬい！
Shiranui!
しらぬ...
Shiranu...
合ってない！合ってない！
We're not in sync! Not in sync!
びよんびよん ぼりんぼりん
Boing boing! Borin borin!
今何も決めてなかったから
We hadn't decided on anything just now.
事前に決めといたほうがいいよね
We should've decided on it beforehand.
適当なんだよなあ
So disorganized.
ということでね、ありがとうございます。
Anyway, thank you very much.
あのさ、しらけんでさ、衣装でさ、揃うのちょっと初めてじゃない？
Hey, isn't this the first time all Shiraken members have matching outfits?
初めて！
First time!
初めてだ！
ちょっとリボンとかよく見て、リボンがかわいいね
Take a good look at the ribbons, they're cute.
かわいい！
Cute!
揃ってるのもかわいい
It's cute that they match.
はい！初めて！
Yes! First time!
すいちゃんと、フレアと、ポルカ、デザインが同じなの
Suichan, Flare, and Polka have the same design.
ほんとだ！一緒！
True! They're the same!
おそろい！
Matching!
あれ？みこちとノエルは？
Huh? What about Miko-chi and Noel?
違うねなんか
Something's different.
仲間はずれだー
We're left out!
今日はね、やっぱり撮影会がしたーい！
Today, I definitely want to have a photo session!
おー！イェーイ！やったやった！
Oh! Yay! We did it!
じゃあファンの皆と一緒にさ
Then, together with all the fans.
撮る！撮る！撮る撮る撮る！
Shoot! Shoot! Shoot shoot shoot!
カメラさーん！
Camera-san!
すごい！かぶってる、君たちかぶってる！
Amazing! You're overlapping, you guys are overlapping!
はい！イェーイ！
Yes! Yay!
みこち真ん中だろう
Miko-chi, you're in the middle.
はい！どやー！
Yes! There!
じゃ社長も真ん中、社長も真ん中
President, you too, President in the middle.
じわーい！はい！
Jwai! Yes!
ポルカ隠れちゃう
Polka's getting hidden.
ポルカ！こっちこい！
Polka! Come here!
イェーイ！素敵！
Yay! Wonderful!
はいすいちゃん！はいみこち！
Yes, Suichan! Yes, Miko-chi!
イェーイ！
Yay!
ラブポーズ
Love pose.
はいノエルノエルノエル！
Yes, Noel Noel Noel!
インベーダー！イェーイ！
Invader! Yay!
なんか寄ってるんだよな
Something's leaning.
ありがとうございます
Thank you very much.
おっ、待って、なんか何何？
Oh, wait, what's this?
なんかいる
Something's there.
みこちだ！ しかもなんかちっちゃくなってない？
It's Miko-chi! And hasn't she gotten small?
みこちみこち！
Miko-chi, Miko-chi!
ちっちゃくなってる！
She's gotten small!
みこちだ！
It's Miko-chi!
みこち一緒に記念撮影しよう
Miko-chi, let's take a commemorative photo together.
せーの、はい！
One, two, go!
はい、みんな！
Okay, everyone!
いっぱいスクショしてね！
Take lots of screenshots!
撮って撮って！
Take them, take them!
ツイートしてねー！
Tweet about it!
みこここだよ、みこここ、ここだよ！
Miko's right here! Miko is right here!
なんか聞こえる... なんか... あれ？
I hear something... what is... huh?
なんなんだよー！
What is this?!
うわああああ！
Uwaaaaaa!
らしさ
Rashisa
自分らしさってなんだろう
I wonder what it means to be myself.
人とは違うで差をつけろ
Set yourself apart by being different from others.
コンビニの雑誌コーナー
In the magazine corner of a convenience store.
表紙に太字で書いてあった
It was written in bold on a cover.
自分らしさってなんだろう
I wonder what it means to be myself.
子供の頃は気にもせず
When I was a kid, I didn't care at all.
気に入らなければ怒って
I'd get angry if I didn't like something.
好きなものを好きだと言って
I'd say I liked the things I liked.
僕らは変わってゆく
We go on changing.
守りたいものが変わってゆく
The things we want to protect go on changing.
理解されない宝物から
From treasures that no one understands,
理解されるための建前へ
to putting up a front to be understood.
大人になるほど
The more we become adults,
後悔する生き物になる
the more we become creatures of regret.
でもね、それでもね
But you know, even so,
見えるものがあるんだよ
there are things that we can see.
だから僕は僕らしく
So I'll be like myself,
そして君は君らしくて
and you'll be like yourself.
始めから探すような
Because it's not something
ものではないんだと思うんだ
that you have to search for from the start.
僕は君じゃないし
I am not you,
君も僕じゃないから
and you are not me.
すれ違う 手を繋ぐ
We pass each other and hold hands,
そこには愛だって生まれる
and even love can be born there.
そういうもんさ
That's just how it is.
自分らしさってなんだろう
I wonder what it means to be myself.
変えられない
It's unchanging,
大切があるから
because there's something precious.
変わりゆく生活が正しい
A changing life is what's right.
個性を出さなきゃいけない
You have to show your individuality.
そういう流行りの無個性で
In that trendy lack of individuality,
悟ったように一歩引いた
you pull back a step as if enlightened,
匿名希望の傍観者
a bystander wishing to remain anonymous.
ちょっと待ってよ星空は
Wait a minute, the starry sky
変わらずあの日と同じだよ
is the same as it was that day.
理解されるとおもちゃ箱は
The toy box that was understood
今でも宝物の筈でしょう
should still be a treasure even now.
ほんとは怖くて
I'm actually scared,
変わらない日々も嫌いで
and I hate the days that don't change.
変わりたくて、変われなくて
Wanting to change, unable to change,
子供の頃を思ったりして
I think back to when I was a child.
見失いそうで
Feeling like I'm losing my way,
自分である意味とか
losing the meaning of being myself.
コンビニで目にした太字は
The bold text I saw at the convenience store
気にしてたんだろう
must have been on my mind.
でもね、それでもね
But you know, even so,
見えるものに気付いてよ
notice the things you can see.
だから僕は僕らしく
So I'll be like myself,
そして君は君らしくて
and you'll be like yourself.
始めから探すような
Because it's not something
ものではないんだと思うんだ
that you have to search for from the start.
僕は君じゃないし
I am not you,
君も僕じゃないから
and you are not me.
すれ違う 手を繋ぐ
We pass each other and hold hands,
そこには愛だって生まれる
and even love can be born there.
そういうもんさ
That's just how it is.
自分らしさってなんだろう
I wonder what it means to be myself.
変えられない
It's unchanging,
大切があるから
because there's something precious.
変わりゆく生活は正しい
A changing life is what's right.
変わりゆく生活が正しい
変わらない
Unchanging,
大切があるから
because there's something precious.
絶対手は抜かない
I'll never slack off
感謝は忘れない
I won't forget my gratitude
決して奢らない
I'll never be boastful
ここに誓います
I swear it here
深い優しさを持って
With deep kindness
強い信念を持って
With strong conviction
誇り高きアイドル 目指してます
I'm aiming to be a proud idol
でも女の子だもん
But I'm a girl
泣いたりもする
And I cry sometimes
焼きもちだって焼くし
I get jealous too
だから
So...
本音を言うとね
To tell you the truth
推し変なんて嫌だ
I hate the idea of you switching favorites
私以外を見てやだ
I hate you looking at anyone but me
推し変なんて許さない
I won't allow you to switch favorites
法律で決まってんの
It's the law
大人ダンスも
Mature dancing too
ちょっぴり苦手だったけど
I was a little bad at it, but
誰より愛を持って
With more love than anyone
アイドルしてます
I'm being an idol
タップ目閉じて
Close your eyes
どんな新曲がいい
What kind of new song should I do?
どんな衣装が見たい
What kind of outfit do you want to see?
一緒に楽しみを 分かち合いたいね
I want to share the fun with you
僕が君のためにあって
I'm here for you
君が僕のためにあって
And you're here for me
そんな理想郷 目指してます
That's the utopia I'm aiming for
でも人は時々ね
But sometimes people
傷つけもする
Cause hurt too
案外弱かったりし
They're unexpectedly weak
だから
So...
本音を言わせて
Let me say what I truly feel
推しにしないでごめんね
Sorry I'm not your top favorite
ファンサだって頑張るから
I'll work hard at fan service
推し増やしたっていいから
It's okay to have more favorites
ガッカリさせないでよね
Just don't disappoint me, okay?
大人ダンスも
Mature dancing too
ちょっぴり苦手だけど
I'm a little bad at it, but
明日を祝う笑顔で
With a smile celebrating tomorrow
アイドルしてます
I'm being an idol
ずっともっともっと
Forever more and more
君に響け 言葉
Let my words reach you
愛の形 振るい立つまま
The shape of love, just as it stirs
なぜか救えたの夢
For some reason, I could save this dream
締め付けられたこの夢
This dream that was constricted
雲に歌いたい
I want to sing to the clouds
会いたい
I want to see you
いつか嫌われたり
Someday I might be hated
忘れられていく
Or gradually forgotten
仕方ないことだけど
It can't be helped, but...
だけど
But...
これだけは君に
Just this, to you...
ずっと歌い続けるよ
I'll keep singing forever
ずっと踊り続けるよ
I'll keep dancing forever
辛いことがあった日は
On days when things are hard
たまに思い出して
Remember this once in a while
ねえ...
Hey...
でもやっぱり
But as I thought
推し変なんて嫌だ
I hate the idea of you switching favorites
私以外を見てやだ
I hate you looking at anyone but me
推し変なんて許さない
I won't allow you to switch favorites
法律で決まってんの
It's the law
大人ダンスも
Mature dancing too
ちょっぴり苦手だったけど
I was a little bad at it, but
誰より愛を持って
With more love than anyone
アイドルしてます
I'm being an idol
タップ目閉じて
Close your eyes
はい！あーあー、３５Ｐ！
Yes! Ah, ah, 35P!
みんなー、楽しんでますかー？
Everyone, are you enjoying yourselves?
はいということで、いやもうすごいノンストップ、
Yes, so, wow, it was non-stop,
ノンストップ、ノンストップ、ノンストップでお送りしました！
non-stop, non-stop, non-stop!
さくらみこ４周年ということで、
This is Sakura Miko's 4th anniversary,
もうね、もうすぐ終わりが近づいております。
and it's already almost time to end.
いやちょっとね、時間も押してしまった
Well, we're a bit behind schedule,
あははという感じなんですけど、
haha, but,
えー皆さんに告知があります。まあみんながもうね分かってる告知からやっていこうかなと思います。
I have an announcement for everyone. I'll start with the announcement you all probably already know.
みんなありがとね、ありがと。ありがとー。
Thank you everyone, thank you. Thank you.
いや、普通にできてよかったよ、ありがとね！
I'm glad I could do it normally, thank you!
それでは、告知どうぞ！
Now, here is the announcement!
はい、さくらみこ活動４周年記念、えーこちらのグッズが出まーす！かわいい！
Yes, Sakura Miko's 4th anniversary commemoration goods are coming out! So cute!
それでは、えー見ていきましょうか。
Now, let's take a look at them.
はい、じゃじゃーん！こちらです。
Yes, ta-da! Here it is.
えー４周年ライブの裏側、B2タペストリー！
The "Behind the Scenes of the 4th Anniversary Live" B2 tapestry!
めちゃくちゃかわいい、これはね。まあ今日たくさんいろんなみこが出てきましたけども！
This is so cute. Well, many different Miko's appeared today!
出てきましたけども、まあそのね裏側となっております。
They did, and this is what's going on behind the scenes.
え、まずは、今日のライブの裏側！かわいい！
First, the cover for today's live! It's so cute!
おるだん先生いつもありがとう！
Ordan-sensei, thank you as always!
そして続いては、ドーン！
And next up is... Bam!
こちら！今回の目玉、
This! The highlight of this lineup,
35Pのみんな、えりーとパーカーとなっております！
the 35P Elite Hoodie!
こちらはですね、まぁ後々わかるんだけど、
This one, well, you'll see why later,
まぁこの特別仕様となっているんですね。何が特別とは言いませんけど。
but it's a special edition. I won't say what makes it special yet.
めっちゃオシャレでしょ、可愛いでしょ、みんな買ってねこれ可愛い、本当に。
It's so stylish and cute. Everyone, please buy it. It's really cute.
しっかりしています。はい、続いて！
It's well-made. Okay, next!
はい！こちらは、
Yes! This one is
みこ＆みこじゃにーのダイカットクッション！
the Miko & Mikojanee die-cut cushion!
なんか、あの、表がさっきのパーカーを着てるみこになっておりまして、
The front side features Miko wearing the hoodie I just showed you,
裏がみこだがいるというね。で側面のデザインも可愛い、なもり先生ありがとう！
and the back has Mikoda. The side design is cute too. Thank you, Namori-sensei!
可愛い。続いて、ドーン！
So cute. Next, bam!
はい、こちらは35Pのみなさんがね、欲しいであろう、
Yes, this is something you 35P probably want,
35Pあんぜん証明書となっております！じゃーん！
the 35P Safety Certificate! Ta-da!
こちらはまぁね、安全を保障されたい35Pが結構いるらしいので、
Since there seem to be many 35P who want their safety guaranteed,
みこが発行してあげました。感謝しろ。
I've issued this for you. Be grateful!
これはね、もうみんなぜひね、チェックしてください。この小さい黒文字は見ないでね。
Please check this out, everyone. Don't look at the small black text, though.
続いて、はい！ということで、こちらがね、フルセットとなっております。
Next! So, here is the full set.
そして購入特典には、なんと、ポポボン！
And as a purchase bonus, we have... drumroll...
はい、ポストカードが付いてきます。
Yes, it comes with a postcard.
こちらは箔押し複製サイン＆メッセージ入りのポストカードです。
This postcard features a foil-stamped replica signature and message.
たくさんね、いっぱい書いたので、皆さんぜひゲットしてね！よろしくなー！わー！
I wrote a lot on it, so please get one! Thanks! Yay!
はぁ、はいということで、急ぎ、急ぎ気味なんだよ。あー、疲れた。
Whew... anyway, I'm kind of in a rush. Man, I'm tired.
あ、お、あれ？お、あれ？
Oh? Hmm? What's this?
お前なんかさ、ちょこちょこ現れやがって！
You... you keep showing up everywhere!
なんなんだよちょっと！しかもなんかちょっと小さくね？小さいんだよなぁ。
What is it now?! And aren't you a bit small? You're definitely tiny.
あ、え、何々？え、告知？あ、告知を...あ、告知を持ってきてくれたの？
Ah, what is it? An announcement? Oh, you brought... an announcement for me?
しかもなんか手紙になってるんだけど。はい、それでは、じゃあ告知何々？こちらどうぞ。
And it's in a letter format. Okay then, let's see what the announcement is. Here we go.
え、何これ？あれ？待って。え、何これ？
Wait, what's this? Huh? Hold on. What is this?
え、これ読んでいいやつ、これ？え？え、なんか、YAGOOから手紙来てるんですけど！
Is it okay for me to read this? Eh? I've received a letter from YAGOO!
え？ちょっと待って。ちょっと待って。それ台本になかったし。いいの？
What? Wait a minute. This wasn't in the script. Is this okay?
これ、時間押してるって言ってたのに。あ、じゃあ、えっと、読ませていただきますね。
They said we were running out of time. Well, alright, I'll read it.
えっと、さくらみこさん、4周年おめでとうございます。
"Sakura Miko-san, congratulations on your 4th anniversary."
VTuberとして活躍できる方を探していた中で、みこさんを見かけて声をかけさせてもらいました。
"While looking for someone who could excel as a VTuber, I saw you and reached out."
そうだったよね、みこ最初ソロスタートだったもんね。びっくりし、ちょっと待って。
That's right, Miko started as a solo project. I was so surprised... wait a sec.
最初はみんなで動画制作を頑張っていましたが、なかなか大変でしたね。
"At first, we all worked hard on video production, but it was quite a struggle."
新しい取り組みもしようとしてお化け屋敷でロケをしたり、
"Trying new things, we even did a location shoot at a haunted house."
その後ライブ配信中心の活動に切り替えて、ホロライブのメンバーも快く受け入れてくれたことで、
"After shifting our focus to livestreaming, and with the Hololive members welcoming you warmly,"
ようやくお本来の強みやポテンシャルを活かして活動できたことに、当時はホッと胸をなでおろしていました。
"I was finally able to breathe a sigh of relief when you could fully utilize your strengths and potential."
色んな行き違いから大変な時期もありましたが、
"There were difficult times due to various misunderstandings,"
打ち合わせでみんなで泣いて頑張っていこうと決めた日のことを今でも覚えています。
"but I still remember the day we all cried in a meeting and decided to keep working hard together."
苦しい時にいい理解者として支えてくれたこともとても感謝しています。
"I am also very grateful that you were such an understanding supporter during the tough times."
今では持ち前のサービス精神と企画力を活かして、ホロライブ運動会やホロファイターなど、
"Now, using your natural spirit of service and planning skills for projects like the Sports Festival and HoloFighters,"
たくさんの視聴者を楽しませたり感動させられる配信を実現していっていることに非常に頼もしく思っていますし、
"I find it very reassuring to see you creating streams that entertain and move so many viewers."
一視聴者としても楽しませてもらっています。
"I personally enjoy them as a viewer as well."
みこさんの頑張りはもちろん、世の中にその時何が求められているかに合わせて柔軟に行動を変えていけたのが良かったと振り返れば思います。
"Looking back, I think it was great that you could adapt your actions flexibly to what the world needed at the time, in addition to your hard work."
新しいことに挑戦することは大変ですが、挑戦しないと始まらないですし、
"Challenging new things is hard, but nothing starts without taking that challenge."
これからも世界中のより多くの人たちを楽しませられるタレントを目指して、色んなことにチャレンジしていってもらえればと思います。
"I hope you continue to challenge various things, aiming to become a talent who can entertain even more people worldwide."
一緒に頑張っていきましょう。よろしくお願いします。
"Let's keep working hard together. Best regards."
2022年8月1日、谷郷元昭。
"August 1, 2022. Motoaki Tanigo."
え、何これ、こんなの渡すの、YAGOO...いやちょっとありがとうございます。
What... giving me something like this... YAGOO... thank you so much.
いやなんかね、これからも頑張ります...。
Well, I'll keep doing my best...
「泣かないんですか？」って言われたんだよね。
I was asked, "Aren't you going to cry?"
いやこんなこと本当に、初めてもらったんですけど...
Well, I've really never received something like this before...
4周年だからね。
Because it's the 4th anniversary.
本当にいろんなことがあったなと、今凄くたくさん振り返ってました。
I was just reflecting on how many things have happened.
ありがとう。みこを誘っていただいて...
Thank you for inviting Miko...
途中にホロライブに参加させていただいて、みんなに本当に支えられております。
I joined Hololive along the way, and I'm really supported by everyone.
みなさま本当にどうもありがとう。
Thank you very much, everyone.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you.
みこちゃん違うでしょ。もっと大事な、告知ありますよね？
Miko-chan, that's not it. There's a more important announcement, right?
はい。それでは告知、ドーン！
Yes. And now for the announcement... Boom!
さくらみこ 1st Album 制作決定！
Sakura Miko 1st Album production decided!
目標のひとつですね、やったー！
That was one of my goals. Yay!
そして...
And...
第一弾は DECO*27 さん作曲！
The first track is composed by DECO*27!
なんとあの神・神・神作曲家、DECO*27さんが作曲してくださいました。
None other than the legendary composer DECO*27 has composed it for me.
それがこちら！ベビーダンス！
And here it is! Baby Dance!
こちらはですね、この後ちょっと時間が押しちゃったので 22時20分からのプレミア公開となっておりますが...
About this, since we're running a bit late, it will have a premiere at 22:20...
皆さん絶対見てね。そして24時には各種音楽サービスで配信があります。
Everyone, please watch it. And at 24:00, it will be available on various music streaming services.
ということで、みこはいろいろダメダメなところもありますし、いろいろ頑張ってやってきたけど...
So, Miko has many flaws and has worked hard in various ways...
夢が一つ叶いましたということで。制作頑張っていこう！
And one of my dreams has come true. Let's work hard on the production!
それじゃ、そんな気になるベビーダンス、みんな聴きたいよね？
Well then, you all want to hear that 'Baby Dance' you're so curious about, right?
新しい髪型もそうだ、きたんだっけね。
Oh right, the new hairstyle too.
それじゃ行ってくるよ、ありがとう！
Well then, here I go. Thank you!
うー、あー、もー、はい！
Ooh, ah, geez, okay!
やだやだミスってらんない、ね？
No, no, I can't afford to mess up, right?
真っ赤なハート差し出して...
Holding out a bright red heart...
そんなのやっぱ妄想じゃん
But that's just a delusion after all
そっちはどう思ってるの
What are you thinking?
言いかけて仕舞う 無理みたい
I start to say it but stop, it seems impossible
こんなんじゃ...ってわかってるんだ
I know it's no good like this
思うほどにハマっていくんだ
The more I think, the more I'm hooked
頑張りたい あたしに期待 ぎゅーだってしたいかも...かもん！
I want to try hard, expect great things from me, I might even want a hug... Come on!
ちょっとは変われていますか？
Have I changed even just a little?
足りないとこばっかだけど
Though I'm full of shortcomings
ポンでコツでドジじゃないあたしだったら きみはだめだよね？
If I wasn't so clumsy and airheaded, you wouldn't like me, right?
ねえ もうやだやだ
Hey, I've had enough
ミスってらんない
I can't afford to mess up
もうやだやだ
I've had enough
踊ってベイビーダンス
Dance the Baby Dance
あたしはまだ諦めない
I'm not giving up yet
でもでも 全然だめかも
But then again, it might be totally hopeless
だってベイビーダンス うまくできないの
Because Baby Dance, I can't do it well
だってベイビーダンス 伝えられないの
Because Baby Dance, I can't convey it
もっと可愛くなりたいのに
I want to become cuter, but...
どうしたらいいとかわかんないし
I don't know what to do
やだやだミスってらんない、ね？
No, no, I can't afford to mess up, right?
あ～やっちまった こんなはずじゃ
Ah, I messed up, it wasn't supposed to be like this
どうして どうして わかっているのに
Why, why, even though I know
見せたくないとこ透けちゃって
The parts I don't want to show are showing through
無理 無理
Impossible, impossible
でも期待はしたいな いいですか？
But I still want to hope, is that okay?
ポンもコツもドジも全部あたしなんだよ
The clumsiness and the mistakes, that's all part of me
ちゃんと見ていてほしい
I want you to look at me properly
ねえ もうやだやだ
Hey, I've had enough
ぐずって後悔
Fretting and regretting
もうやだやだ
I've had enough
回ってベイビーダンス
Spinning Baby Dance
だめなあたし塗り替えたい
I want to rewrite my flawed self
でもでも 全然だめかも
But then again, it might be totally hopeless
だってベイビーダンス うまくできないの
Because Baby Dance, I can't do it well
だってベイビーダンス 伝えられないの
Because Baby Dance, I can't convey it
もっと可愛くなりたいのに
I want to become cuter, but...
どうしたらいいとかわかんないし
I don't know what to do
まだまだいけるかな
Can I still keep going?
まだまだ言えるかな
Can I still say it?
まだまだできるかな
Can I still do it?
まだまだ...うぅ...
Still... ugh...
ポンでコツでドジでだめで 足りないとこばっかだって
Clumsy, airheaded, a mess, full of shortcomings
きっとやめないんだ
But I'm sure I won't stop
ポンでコツでドジでだめで 足りないとこばっかだって
Clumsy, airheaded, a mess, full of shortcomings
見ていてほしい
I want you to watch me
ねえ もうやだやだ
Hey, I've had enough
ミスってらんない
I can't afford to mess up
もうやだやだ
I've had enough
踊ってベイビーダンス
Dance the Baby Dance
あたしはまだ諦めない
I'm not giving up yet
ほらほら 全然だめじゃない
Look, look, it's not totally hopeless
だってベイビーダンス うまくできるから
Because Baby Dance, I can do it well
だってベイビーダンス 伝えられるから
Because Baby Dance, I can convey it
もっと可愛くなりたいから
Because I want to become cuter
どんな時だってそう 頑張れるし
No matter the time, I can do my best,
だってベイビーダンス
Because, Baby Dance,
きみに届くまで
Until it reaches you,
だってベイビーダンス
Because, Baby Dance,
きみに会えるまで
Until I can see you,
もっと可愛くなりたいから
Because I want to become even cuter,
どんな時だってそう 頑張れるし
No matter the time, I can do my best,
やだやだ！ ミスってらんない、ね？
No way, no way! I can't afford to mess up, okay?
愛言葉IV / 詞·曲 DECO*27 / 歌 さくらみこ
Ai Kotoba IV / Lyrics & Comp. DECO*27 / Vocal Sakura Miko
そう、そう、なんてしてなかった
Yes, yes, I wasn't doing anything like that,
弱音 本音 君もそう思った？
Complaints, true feelings, did you think so too?
最高で止まらないように信じたい
I want to believe so that the best doesn't stop.
叶えたい夢まであとどれくらい
How much longer until the dream I want to fulfill?
誰も行ったことがない場所へ
To a place where no one has ever been,
辿り着くまで僕は止まれない
I won't stop until I get there.
たぶんしんどいけど どうかよろしくね
It'll probably be tough, but please look after me.
ねぇねぇ、たまに愛でて 僕だけじゃ作れないもの
Hey, hey, cherish it sometimes, the things I can't create alone,
僕ときみで形出した過去とか今とかまとめて全部
The past and the present that you and I shaped, all together.
きみを置いてどっか行っちゃうとかあり得ないよ
Leaving you behind and going somewhere is impossible.
きみがくれた音に弾けた暇に
In the leisure that burst into the sounds you gave me,
初めましてからずっと恋してるんだよ
I've been in love with you ever since we first met.
きみのいない未来考えられないよ
I can't imagine a future without you.
これからの先も二人がいいじゃん
Isn't it better for the two of us to be together from now on too?
一途になるほど逃げたくもなったよ
The more earnest I became, the more I wanted to run away.
散々な僕のこと呼んでくれてありがとう
Thank you for calling out to my terrible self.
きみのいない未来考えられないよ
I can't imagine a future without you.
これからの先も二人で、それがいいじゃん
The two of us together from now on too, that's what I want.
妄想 膨らんでくストーリー
Delusion, the story that expands,
感傷 やけに凹んじゃって
Sentimentality, I ended up getting really depressed,
願書 求めすぎはやーやー
Application, asking for too much is a no-no,
終わんないアレは運命でしょ
That which doesn't end must be fate, right?
ねぇねぇ、おいいでいで 僕が君にできること
Hey, hey, come here, come here, the things I can do for you,
まだまだまだまだあるけど 驚かせたいから内緒なんだ
There are still so many more, but I want to surprise you, so it's a secret.
きみの愛がいつも勝っちゃうこと 許さないよ、うぇーい
I won't forgive the fact that your love always wins, yay!
みんな！ 4周年祝ってくれて本当にありがとうございます！
Everyone! Thank you so much for celebrating my 4th anniversary!
これからも応援よろしくね！
Please keep supporting me from now on too!
きみ以外はヤダ わがままはバカ
I don't want anyone but you, selfishness is stupid,
変わらないときめきは
With unchanging excitement,
熱唱したのわバカ
Singing my heart out, I'm a fool.
きみがくれた音に弾けた暇に
In the leisure that burst into the sounds you gave me,
初めましてからずっと恋してるんだよ
I've been in love with you ever since we first met.
きみのいない未来考えられないよ
I can't imagine a future without you.
これからの先も二人がいいじゃん
Isn't it better for the two of us to be together from now on too?
一途になるほど逃げたくもなったよ
The more earnest I became, the more I wanted to run away.
散々な僕のこと呼んでくれてありがとう
Thank you for calling out to my terrible self.
きみのいない未来考えられないよ
I can't imagine a future without you.
これからの先も二人で、それがいいじゃん
The two of us together from now on too, that's what I want.
僕らヴァンパイア いいよ吸っちゃっていいよ
We are Vampires, it's okay, you can suck it,
この歌った歌って、君が輝けるように
I sang this song so that you could shine.
はい、ということで、4周年祝ってくれてみんな、ありがとね！
Yes, so, thank you everyone for celebrating my 4th anniversary!
この後、ベイビーダンスは22時20分にプレミア公開！
After this, 'Baby Dance' will have its premiere at 22:20!
そして、22時30分からはメン限もあります！見に来てね！
And from 22:30, there's also a members-only stream! Come watch!
みんな本当に、本当にいつもありがとう！大好きだよー！
Everyone, really, thank you so much for everything as always! I love you!